{
    "id": "fc34bc466d96495792bbd167d4cac1c8",
    "title": "Simple past or present perfect?",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5e8d6f5634b04148b3576f891c847494",
            "title": "Simple Past Or Present Perfect",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… in this city when I was a child.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "lived",
                        "have lived"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Nobody ………………….. him since yesterday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "saw",
                        "has seen"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘Where is John?’ ‘He ………………… here ten minutes ago.’",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "has been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ………………… last year.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "died",
                        "has died"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ………………….. since she left school.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was unemployed",
                        "has been unemployed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They ………………….. the contract last week.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "signed",
                        "have signed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The film …………………… . yet.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "has not been released",
                        "was not released"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She …………………. ill since she returned from Malaysia.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "has been",
                        "was"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I …………………. your brother yesterday.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "met",
                        "have met"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Look. Somebody ………………….. their umbrella behind.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "left",
                        "has left"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}